That man also knows...
那个男人也知道…
Are you going to marry a septuagenarian?
你要嫁给一个七旬老人吗
Your expression is getting more and more interesting the more I look at it
你这表情真是越看越有趣
If that kid knew, it would be more interesting
那小子如果知道了  感觉会更有趣
Hello
喂
Say it yourself
你自己说
I am...who?
我是…谁呢
Didn't you say you were an uninvited guest?
你不是说自己是不速之客吗
Then let's take it for granted.
那便好好当一次吧
This…
这位…
Just the man I'm attracted to
正是我所倾心的男子
And we are getting married soon
而且我们即将成婚了
By the way, this is an officer from the Bureau of Robbery.
对了  这位是捕盗厅的从事官
As for the name…
至于名字…
pleasure
悦
this is my name
这就是我的名字
If it goes as you said
若照你所说的
I have no interest in sharing my first name with you right now.
我现在并没有与你通名报姓的兴致
So that’s it for introducing each other.
那互相介绍就到此为止吧
It's dark. I don't know why you came here.
夜色已深  不知你来这里是因为何事
Just think of it as disciplining the family.
就当作是在管束家眷吧
Hello Eunjo
喂  恩祖
Did you come here with my young master?
你和我家少爷一起来的吗
young master
少爷
How much wine did you drink?
你到底喝了多少酒啊
What's going on with the blood on your face?
脸上的血是怎么回事
are you injured
你受伤了吗
You stand up first
你先站起来吧
Has Zai Yi left?
载伊已经走了吗
future in-laws
未来的亲家
Okay…
好了…
You stand up first
你先站起来
When will that guy Enzu come over?
恩祖那家伙什么时候才要过来
Didn't you say you'd come over after your shift?
不是说值完班就过来吗
Are you delaying treatment because you are helping someone again?
该不会又在帮谁治疗而耽误了吧
Yes
是啊
How can such a good life be without my benefactor?
这种好日子  怎么能少了我家恩祖
That's right
就是啊
Start with me
从我开始说起
Is there anyone here who has not received help from Eunjo?
这里有谁没受过恩祖的帮忙呢
That's right, that's right
没错　　对啊
no one
没有人
Come on…
来吧…
Who is Eunjo?
恩祖是谁
She
她啊
It's that Dr. Hong who works at the Huimin Office.
就是那位洪医女  在惠民署当差
Welfare Department
惠民署
My adults should be there too.
我家大人应该也在那里啊
Hello
喂
The word "discipline"
「管束」这个词
It's a word that people like me, who are law-abiding, would use.
是像我这样秉法守规的人才会用的词
Is this what you should say to a woman who is about to get married?
岂是对即将成婚的女子该说的话？
I'm not talking about her
我不是在说她
What I am controlling is the way you, the officer, look at her.
我在管束的是从事官你  看着她的眼神
Then you can see it quite clearly
那你还看得挺清楚的
unfortunately
不幸的是
She has just drawn an insurmountable line for me
她刚才已向我划下不可逾越之界线
In other words
换言之
She has always been well-behaved and has never had to be disciplined.
她素行端正  从未有须受管束之事
This will not be possible in the future
日后亦无此可能
As a future husband, you should at least know this
身为未来夫君  至少该知道这点
When are you going to punch?
你何时要出拳呢
It looks like he's about to punch. I'd better get out of the way first.
看那气势好像要出拳了  我最好先避开
I've always been more mature
我向来比较成熟
It’s no longer the age to shake fists at every turn
已经不是动不动就挥拳的年纪了
Besides, in my capacity
再说了  以我的身份来说
Mostly swords are used
用的多半是剑
If you want to make things easier, I can also give you poisonous wine directly.
若要方便行事  也能直接赐你毒酒
It's scary. Should I be scared?
真吓人  我应该要害怕吗
if necessary
如果有必要的话
Why are so many people in the world attracted to these women?
为何世上有如此多人  倾心于此等女子
What you said has been very unpleasant since just now.
你说的话从刚才起  就很令人不快啊
because that's the truth
因为那是事实
That girl was just sold to our house
那个丫头不过是被卖到我们家
She can only be regarded as a concubine at best...
充其量只能算作小妾的…
I really can't listen anymore
我实在听不下去了
I treated you politely just now because you are the person Hong Enzu is going to marry.
刚才以礼相待  只因为你是洪恩祖将嫁之人
what are you doing
你们在做什么
what is this doing
这是在做什么
get out of the way
让开
why do this
为什么要这样做
How interesting
真是有趣啊
Please go back
请你回去吧
Thank you for your help during this time
感谢你这段时间的帮助
From now on we won't meet again
从今以后  我们别再见面了
Eunjo Hong Eunjo
恩祖  洪恩祖
Enzu
恩祖
What's going on with this triangular confrontation?
这三角对峙的场面是怎么回事
This atmosphere…
这种气氛…
We should get to know each other and leave, right?
我们应该要识相离开才对吧
Everyone just took ten steps back
全体就这样  向后退十步
one two three…
一  二  三…
I'm here too
我也来了
I knew you were here
我就知道你在这里
As long as you know, come here
知道就好  过来
What's wrong? Isn't the person there?
怎么了  人不是在那里吗
wait a moment
等一下
I will go back with you as an officer.
从事官跟你们一起回去
That's what I meant
正有此意
Go ahead and ask
你去问吧
Aren't you the right-hand man of the great king?
你不是大君大人的左右手吗
Aren't you also the confidant of the great king?
你不也是大君大人的心腹吗
Sir
大人
What happened between you and Dr. Hong?
你和洪医女之间发生了什么事吗
Sir…
大人…
I apologize to you on his behalf for what happened just now.
刚才的事  我代替他向你道歉
Looks like I'm not an uninvited guest
看来我并非不速之客
Instead, I helped you.
反而是帮了你一把
It actually has both
竟然两者都有呢
Then your expression should be happier, right?
那你的表情应该要开心点吧
At least I helped you keep it
至少我帮你保住了
The last self-esteem you don’t want to be seen through by a man who likes you
不想被喜欢你的男人看穿的最后自尊
So they were so happy
于是他们就这样幸福地
live for a long time
长长久久地生活下去
Even as a wicked girl
就算是以孽女的身分
Maybe I’d also imagine being remembered like this.
可能也想象这样被记住吧
I didn't mean anything else, but that's it
我没有别的意思  不过就是这样
It's okay for you to tell him now
你现在去告诉他也无妨
If you want to trample even that point...
如果连那一点都要践踏的话…
I will take this debt back today fiercely.
今天这笔债  我会狠狠讨回来
please
请便
Those two gentlemen
那两位公子
It seems like there was a big fight over Eunjo.
似乎为了恩祖大打出手了一场吧
Who is that young man next to you?
旁边那位公子是谁
What a mystery
这可真是个谜啊
You are here
你来了啊
Looking at his posture, he looks like he is the son of a wealthy family.
看那架势  好像是大户人家的公子
Did Dr. Hong ever tell me who he was?
洪医女有说过他是谁吗
She never mentioned it
她绝口不提啊
When I saw her in the morning, her face was quite gloomy.
早上见到她  脸色还挺阴沉的
What about our senior official?
那我们的从事官大人呢
He is absent from work today
他今天缺勤
Having said that
话说回来
Have you heard anything about Ji Dong?
你们有没有听到什么关于吉童的事
What happened to Ji Tong?
吉童又怎么了
Could it be because of that rumor?
该不会是因为那个传闻吧
Rumor?
传闻吗
End it quickly
快点结束吧
Have you checked it out?
查清楚了吗
This is Lord Du Chengzhi’s eldest son
这是都承旨大人的长子
Items brought back from the Ming Dynasty to be transported to the palace
自明朝带回  准备运进宫里的物品
Isn't this a seed?
这不是种子吗
where is this to be used
这是要用在何处
I've been feeling extremely sleepy and weak lately
近来总觉得格外困倦无力
The weather is getting warmer, so you will be so sleepy, right?
天气回暖  才会如此困倦吧
Right
对了
Where did Lord Daoyue get that document?
道月大君那份文书  是从哪里得来的呢
It is said that I picked it up by accident.
据说是偶然捡到的
Your Highness will not believe this statement, right?
殿下该不会相信这种说法吧
As long as my stepmother is alive
只要我那位继母还活着
It seems like there are some fun old stories between the brothers.
看来兄弟之间  是有些好玩的旧事啊
I'm sleepy
寡人困了
All agree
都承旨
Now that it's over, what else can there be to say in response?
既是已了之事  还能有什么可回应的呢
No, it seems that I am overly worried.
不  看来是臣过度担忧了
The position of Da Sijian is still vacant.
大司谏的位置还空着
Who should be put in this position...
该让谁坐上这个位置呢…
Hong Minzhi
洪民直
He is an old friend of yours, right?
是都承旨你的故交吧
Even now, I am still looking for Superintendent Hong Minzhi.
事到如今还在找洪民直大监
It’s really hard to understand the Lord’s thoughts
主上的心思实在很难搞懂
He wants them all
他全部都要
The force of tyrants and the achievements of saintly kings
暴君的武力以及圣君的功绩
Don't miss anything
一件都不放过
Superintendent Hong’s so-called blunt advice
洪大监所谓的直言谏言
They are all threatening my father.
全都在威胁父亲啊
If the father cannot decide, then leave it to the child.
若父亲无法决定  那就交给孩儿吧
Didn’t Superintendent Hong stay ill for many years after he collapsed in the Gengwu year?
洪大监不是庚午年倒下后  卧病多年
Didn't wake up until a year ago?
直到一年前才醒来吗
Even if he died today and tomorrow, no one would be suspicious...
即使今明两日身亡  也未尝会有人起疑…
Be careful with your words
说话谨慎点
He is my best friend in this life
他是我此生的知己
Please inform His Highness on my behalf
请代我禀告殿下
I still don't have full freedom of movement
我仍未能完全行动自如
Are you refusing?
你这是拒绝吗
If I sit back in the position of chief minister again,
若我再坐回大司谏之位
Sooner or later my family will
我的家人迟早有一天
Will we encounter disaster like the Gengwu Year again?
会再次遭遇庚午年那样的劫数
I can't let that child Eunjo
我不能让恩祖那孩子
Bear that pain again
再次承受那般痛苦
Why are you so sure of the outcome?
你为何如此笃定结局
Because I am a person who cannot bend down
因为我这个人  弯不下腰
How about taking a teaching position in a college?
不然去书院担任教席如何
I can write a recommendation letter for you
我可以替你写荐书
That salary is enough to support the family.
那份俸禄  足以养家糊口了
Always take care of you
总是承蒙你的照顾
Pingyan thank you
平岩  谢谢你
It's my turn to thank you
是我该向你道谢才对
Save me from being the shameless person who takes the life of my best friend
让我不用成为夺走知己性命的无耻之人
Should we ask them to retreat first?
要不要让他们先退下呢
I heard that the empress had an uneasy sleep at night
听说娘娘夜里睡得不安稳
My night sleep has long been dedicated to my only child
我的夜眠啊  早已奉献给唯一的孩子了
On the other hand, the face of Zhongdian is not very good either.
倒是中殿的脸色也不太好
I am also because of my only husband...
我也因那唯一的夫君…
Please forgive me for omitting the following
以下恕我省略
Fortunately, there is still a nave in this deserted palace.
幸好这冷清的宫殿里还有中殿在
Not long ago, the king entered Kangnyeong Palace
不久前大君入了康宁殿的事
You should have heard about it
你应该有所耳闻吧
yes
是的
What on earth was he thinking that he went to see the Lord alone?
他到底抱着什么心思  居然单独去觐见主上
Although the inside story is unknown
内情虽不得而知
But judging from the results, we are brothers who are of the same mind
但从结果来看  正是兄弟同心
Eliminate corrupt officials
铲除了贪官污吏
Just treat it as such
就当作是如此吧
The Lord’s temptation must have a reason
主上的试探  必是事出有因
Have you forgotten what happened in the Gengwu Year?
你忘记了庚午年的事了吗
Then wait for the tragedy...
那等惨案…
How could it be forgotten so easily
怎么可能轻易遗忘
I said unnecessary things
是我说了多余的话
Let's not talk about politics here.
我们别在这里谈政事了
Right
对了
I'm also inquiring about Maharaja's marriage.
我也在打听大君的婚事
Really?
真的吗
Concubine
大妃娘娘
Is the Maharaja inside?
大君在里面吗
I must finalize the marriage today...
我今日一定要敲定婚事…
Why is the imperial doctor also there...
为何御医也在…
Is Yue'er sick?
悦儿生病了吗
No other symptoms
并无其他病症
Just these few days...
只是这几日…
Feeling extremely restless
心绪极其不宁
It’s really…
真是…
Why is this music so sad?
这乐曲为何如此凄凉
Didn’t I tell you to boost your spirits?
不是叫你们要提振兴致吗
My stomach hurts
肚好痛
Don't you think it's funny?
你都不觉得好笑吗
Why is it funny
为什么好笑
Because I'm laughing
因为我在笑啊
I already said I want to laugh, can't you agree with me?
我都说了想笑  你就不能附和我吗
How about grabbing it?
要不抢过来如何
Spot the mole first, then take revenge
先点痣  然后再报仇
what do you think
你觉得如何
Sir
大人
I am the king of this country
我是这个国家的大君
If you want to grab it, are you afraid that you won't be able to grab it?
如果要抢的话  还怕抢不到吗
I'll show you
我会让你们见识
What is omnipresent power?
什么才叫无所不至的权势
She was completely unmoved
她完全不为所动
The wealth and power I have
我所拥有的财富、权势
status, bearing, appearance
地位、气度、容貌
Most people are tempted by just one of these items
一般人只是其中一项  就足以动心
She just won't be tempted by anything.
她偏偏哪一样都不会动心
This is from the Royal Medical Clinic
这是御医所呈上
A document recording the illness of your Majesty
记载着大君大人病症的文书
The Empress ordered that the disease be spread to medical clinics across the country
大妃娘娘下令将病症广传至全国医馆
Gathering everyone’s wisdom to find out the name of the disease
集众人之智  共同查明病名
Fire sickness?
火病？
Could it be madness?
该不会是狂症吧？
do you have any ideas
你有什么想法吗
Are you asking me?
是在问我吗
Now we need everyone to come up with ideas
现在正需要大家一起出主意
Even just one person’s idea is important
就算只有一个人的想法也很重要
Don't worry too much. Let's listen.
别顾虑太多  说来听听吧
Happy, Angry, Worry, Thought, Sadness, Fear, Surprise
喜  怒  忧  思  悲  恐  惊
From the point of view of disorder of the seven emotions
根据七情紊乱这点来看
I'd venture to guess that I might be suffering from depression.
小的斗胆猜测  恐怕是郁症
Don’t you think that Maharaja’s symptoms are very similar to lovelorn?
你不觉得  大君大人的症状很像失恋吗
Lovelorn?
失恋吗
Is that so?
是这样吗
From today on we won't meet again
从今天起  我们别再见面了
That's what I meant
正有此意
Lovelorn…
失恋…
Is it such a painful thing?
是这么痛苦的事吗
what did you say
你说什么
nothing
没什么
How can anyone dare to get rid of the Maharaja?
哪有人敢甩掉大君大人呢
On the contrary, I think it was a wise move for the medical woman to reject you.
我反而觉得那位医女拒绝你是明智之举
Meet and separate rashly
轻率地相识又分离
Wouldn't it be of no use to her?
对她来说岂不是毫无益处吗
Who said I was rash?
谁说我轻率了？
Are you planning to take her as your concubine?
那你是打算纳她为妾吗
Not married yet
都还没成婚
If the concubine knew about it
如果被大妃娘娘知道
There will definitely be a fuss afterwards
之后肯定会闹得鸡飞狗跳
You made your wishful thinking too early
你的如意算盘打得太早了
Not to mention it was a trick, it didn't even start.
别说是耍花招了  根本就没能开始
That's right
就是啊
Since it hasn't started yet
既然没有开始
Of course there is nothing to forget
当然也就没什么好忘记的
Yes
有啊
Her face is still imprinted in my mind
她的脸庞还印在我的脑海之中
Your expression is getting more and more interesting the more I look at it
你这表情真是越看越有趣
To put it bluntly, I really don’t like that medical woman.
说句难听话  我对那个医女实在没什么好感
They already have fiancés
都已经有未婚夫了
Why did I do that to you that night?
那天晚上为什么还要那样对你
Here we go again, I really can’t stand it
又来了  真受不了
what's going on
那是怎么回事
Destroyed?
破坏的破？
Are you praying for their relationship to break up now?
现在是在祈祷他们的感情破裂吗
Lord Superintendent
大监大人
Are you ready to leave the palace?
你要准备出宫了吧？
Do you want to walk back together?
要不要一起走回去？
are you waiting for me
你是在等我吗
can't i do this
我不能这样做吗
Of course that's good
当然好啊
what are you thinking
你在想什么
This scene feels strange to me
这幅光景令我感到陌生
Until a year ago you were still bedridden
直至一年前你都还卧病在床
I never thought I'd be able to walk with you like this
我从未想过能像这样与你同行
Pingyan recommended a position to me
平岩向我推荐了一个职位
He said there is an academy in Nanyuan that needs teachers
他说南原有间书院需要老师
I agreed
我便应允了
Do you actually have to go that far away?
竟然要到那么远的地方吗
With your current physical condition, it should be difficult for you to bear the burden.
就你现在的身体状况  应该还难以负荷才对
Not too forced
不会太勉强的
Instead of wasting time here
与其在这里虚度光阴
Maybe it wouldn't be so hard to teach there.
去那里教书或许不会这么难挨
When do you plan to leave?
那你计划何时出发？
I'm leaving in a few days
这几天内就要出发了
Should arrive on the day classes start
应该会在开课当天抵达
So will you set off before the wedding?
那你会在婚礼前启程吗
Yeah, what a pity
是啊  真是可惜
It turns out that the adults made this trip because they couldn’t let go.
原来大人是因为放不下心才会跑这一趟
Leaving before the wedding might be a good thing
在婚礼前离开  说不定是好事一桩
How I want to see your rouged face
我多想看看你那点上胭脂的脸庞啊
I will cheer up
我会提起精神
Have a good wedding
好好地举办婚礼
Then let me help you prepare the medicinal materials you need to take on the way.
那我先帮你备好路上要服用的药材
You don't have to worry
你不用急
If you want to find good medicinal materials
如果想找到好药材
You have to start looking for it now
要从现在就开始物色才行
Even as a wicked woman
就算是以孽女的身分
Maybe I’d also imagine being remembered like this.
可能也想象这样被记住吧
Are you planning how to break off the engagement again?
你又在盘算要怎样退婚吗
Don't use admiration as a pretext
别拿爱慕之情那套来搪塞
What's the real reason you want to ruin your marriage?
你想毁掉婚事的真正理由是什么
where are you going
你要去哪里
to ruin this marriage.
去毁掉这桩婚事
The king actually had a relationship with a medical woman
大君竟与一介医女有所来往
Other than that, there is nothing unusual
除此之外没有什么异状
However, the young master met the Maharaja at the Huimin Office before going back.
不过小少爷曾在惠民署与大君碰面后才回去
Now I can finally see my father.
现在才终于能见到爹一面呢
I've been here several times but all failed, and I feel deeply disappointed.
我来过好几次都扑空  深感失落
Who did you just go see?
你刚去见过谁？
What's going on with this concern-filled question?
充满关心的这个问题是怎么回事
I don't seem to deserve this kind of treatment
我似乎不配得到这种对待
Yes
是啊
Your only advantage is that you know how many layers you have
你唯一的优点就是懂得自己有几两重
Dad
爹
I overheard your conversation with your mother
我无意间听见你与娘的对话
Am I not my mother’s biological flesh and blood?
难道我并非娘的亲生骨肉
Is he the son of a prostitute from a humble background?
而是出身卑贱的妓生之子吗
so stupid
真是愚蠢
If you pretend not to hear
你如果装作没听见
At least I can deceive myself
起码还能自欺欺人
Then why do you want me to grow up as your eldest son?
那为何要让我以嫡长子的身分长大
Is it because dad only has one son, his elder brother?
难道是因为爹只有兄长一个儿子吗
you don't need to be disappointed
你不需要感到失望
To seal the mouth of your prostitute mother
为了封住你那妓生母亲的嘴
I paid a lot of price
我可是付出了不少代价
So you are not worthless
因此你并不是毫无价值可言
The livestock sold cost a lot of money.
卖掉的牲畜可是所费不赀
Are you taking credit from me?
你这是在跟我邀功吗
I have already helped you get the number one scholar that your government is so eager for.
贵府这么渴求的状元  我已经帮忙考上
In the future, I will also get you the official position you want.
将来也会为你谋得属意的官职
Now it's my turn to take some credit
现在也该轮到我邀点功了
Please cancel your marriage to the Zhongdian family
请退掉和中殿家族的婚事
I don't want to be a stud who just sows seeds
我并不想当只负责播种的种马
It's a pity that your usefulness only ends here
可惜你的用处就仅止于此
I don't want to imitate someone
我并不想效仿某人
Let any defective products come out
让任何瑕疵品问世
So you just want to ruin my good deeds?
所以你就想毁了我的好事吗
See you are so angry
看你如此愤怒
It seems that I should have succeeded
看来我应该是成功了
are you injured
你受伤了吗
This guy...
这小子…
What happened to him
他是怎么了
Have you mentioned the secret record to Zai Yi?
你有跟载伊提过秘录的事吗
No
没有
Didn’t you say it’s not yet time?
你不是说还不到时候吗
This is the medicine we adults need to take
这是我们大人要服用的药材
Please take more trouble
麻烦你多费心
No problem
没问题
Come
来
she is smiling again
她又在笑了
What's so funny
到底有什么好笑的
Uncle, please give me a pound of Huang Qi.
大叔  这个黄耆也给我一斤吧
what are you doing
你这是在做什么
Didn’t I say I would ask you to repay me twice as much?
我不是说会要你加倍奉还吗
Let me go, I tell you to let me go
放手  我叫你放开我
Are you like this because of what happened last time?
你是因为上次的事才这样吗
I think you are an eyesore
我觉得你很碍眼
What happened to me
我又怎么了
A mere evil girl dares to act like a younger sister
区区一个孽女也敢摆出妹妹的架子
What else does Shen Qing sacrifice for his blind father?
还有什么沈清为了盲父牺牲奉献
He even dreamed of being happy until old age
甚至还妄想着要幸福快乐到老
All this is an eyesore to me
这一切都让我觉得碍眼
It's better to live a miserable life
倒不如过着不幸的日子算了
Don't just smile when nothing happens
不要没事就笑嘻嘻的
Even if it’s crying, getting angry, or being resentful, that’s fine
哪怕是哭闹、发火、怨恨都好
Because in real life
因为在现实生活中
There is no emperor who will come forward to rescue Shen Qing
并没什么天子会出面解救沈清
So what is your conclusion?
所以你的结论是什么
Do you want me to break off the engagement again?
又要叫我退婚吗
This marriage…
这场婚事…
No
不
It should be a transaction
应该是交易才对
This deal…
这场交易…
as you said
正如你所说
She's just a naughty girl like me
不过是我这种孽女
Just a struggle to survive
为了活下去的挣扎而已
So I can't give up easily
所以我没办法轻言放弃
thank you for your charity
多谢你的施舍
Why are you so careless?
怎么这么不小心
What's going on? What's your expression?
怎么回事  你那是什么表情
I asked you what happened
我问你是怎么回事
Is something wrong?
是不是有什么事
Of course I would be frightened if you appeared out of nowhere.
你突然冒出来  我当然会被吓到啊
Why are you here...
你怎么会在这…
Are you here to find me?
难道是来找我的吗
Don't be sentimental
你别自作多情
I originally wanted to answer you like this
我本来想这样回答你
But you were right
但被你说对了
I went to the Huimin Office
我去了趟惠民署
I heard you were looking for a medicine dealer
结果听说你来找药材商
So I chased after him relentlessly.
所以就死缠烂打地追过来了
why are you looking for me
你为什么要找我
when are you going to get married
你什么时候要成婚
Next year? Or the year after tomorrow?
明年？还是后年？
It's no good if we keep bumping into each other
一直碰到面都没好事
It's better not to give him hope
还是别给他希望比较好
Ten days later
十天后
Ten days…
十天…
I'm afraid we don't have time to flirt or laugh.
我们恐怕没时间打情骂俏、谈笑风生
Enjoy the atmosphere and get to know each other better
享受气氛跟深入了解彼此了
what
什么
what do you like
你喜欢什么
Food, scenery, jewelry, paintings, or musical preferences?
食物、风景、珠宝、画作  还是音乐喜好？
No. Where is a better place to start?
不  从哪开始比较好？
That... where is the nearest cloth shop?
那个…最近的布庄在哪里？
We need to go there first
我们要先去那里一趟才行
Wait, wait a moment
等等  你先等一下
Are you kidding me now?
你现在是在开玩笑吧？
If I just wanted to make a joke
我如果只想开玩笑的话
Will I cling to you like this without respecting myself?
会像这样不讲自尊地缠着你不放吗
Am I the only one who thinks this is sudden?
只有我觉得这情况很突然吗
Me too
我也一样
This kind of behavior is no different from that of a lunatic.
这种行为已经跟疯子没什么分别了
It turns out that on the day we first met
原来在我们初次见面那天
I didn't make a mistake
我并没有看走眼
Just think of the fool part as prescient.
傻瓜这部分就当作是你有先见之明吧
Have you forgotten?
你是不是忘记了？
What about me?
我呢
My fiancé is the only one in my heart
心里只有我未婚夫一人
That guy treats you...
那家伙对你…
Why are so many people in the world attracted to these women?
为何世上有如此多人  倾心于此等女子
So disgusting
真让人反胃
Very annoying
很讨人厌
Are you sure it's the same person as the one from a few days ago?
你确定跟前几天那位是同一个人吗
Or are you just so unreasonable?
还是你原本就这么蛮不讲理？
If I am really being unreasonable
我如果真的很蛮不讲理的话
You can't do anything to me at all
你根本就拿我没办法
The reason why I didn’t ask about your fiancé’s family background
我之所以没过问你未婚夫的家世
It's because I want to use all the coercive means I can use
是因为我想把能动用的强制手段
Saved until the last moment
保留到最后一刻的缘故
I don't want to become a mean person
我不希望自己变成卑鄙小人
I hope you can endure it as much as possible
希望能尽量忍耐
I'm trying to make you change your mind.
试着让你改变心意才会这样做
I really can't understand
我是真的无法理解
How many times have you met me?
你到底跟我见过几次面？
How many times do we need to see each other again?
那到底还要再见过几次才够？
If I want you to understand why I do this
如果要让你理解我为何这样做的话
No…
不…
I won't bother to understand
我就不费心理解了
I'm leaving first
我先走了
Be careful on your way
你路上小心
You'd better be honest
你还是坦白一点吧
Are you trying to run away from me now?
你现在是想从我身边逃走啊
because you are scared
因为你害怕了
Afraid?
害怕？
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
You know it well yourself
你自己也心知肚明啊
I reiterate
我再重申一次
Me to my fiancé…
我对我的未婚夫…
You must not be in love, right?
你们肯定不恩爱吧？
If that's the case
若真是那样
Then how come you did that night...
那你那天晚上怎么会…
I originally planned to go along with your improvised lie.
我原本打算配合你那个临时编出的谎言
When you draw the line and push me away
当你划清界线  将我推开时
I also thought about simply pretending not to know and turning around.
我也曾想过干脆装作不知情就此转身
But I don't want to do that
但我不想那样做了
So…
所以…
Good
好
I'll tell you the truth
我就老实跟你说吧
That's right, that night
没错  就是那天晚上
I decided that night that I was going to have a
我在那晚决定要举办一场
People like me in North Korea
朝鲜像我这种身份的人
Most people choose marriage
大多都会选择的婚姻
for me
对我而言
wealth, success, fame
财富、成功、名誉
My family and even myself
家人  乃至于我自己
Among the many things that people value
在世人所重视的诸多事物中
What I thought was the least relevant to me
我原以为与自己最不相干的
It's love
就是爱情
But the night I made up my mind to get married
然而就在我下定决心要成婚的那晚
This is the first time I asked myself
我才第一次问自己
If I…
如果我…
What should I do if I miss something important?
因而错失了什么重要的东西该怎么办？
This question makes me very uneasy
这个问题令我很不安
It seems that I have also made myself very unlucky.
好像也搞到自己很不幸
That's when I saw you
就在那个时候  我看见了你
I saw a man who had been waiting for me for more than two hours
看到一个等了我超过两个时辰的男人
Suddenly I felt like I had become the protagonist in a folk legend
突然觉得自己像是成为了民间传说里的主角
That's it
就只是这样
escape reality
逃离现实
Run to you
奔向你身边
Blinded by self-pity
被自怨自艾蒙蔽了双眼
casually to a strange man
随意地对一个陌生男人
pour out one's misfortune
倾吐自己的不幸
But I don't want to be stuck with that story now
但我现在不想被那个故事困住了
lie
说谎
Please stop following me
请你别再跟着我不放
I'm the one who got dumped
被甩掉的人是我
Why are you angry instead?
为什么反而是你在生气
I just need one sentence
我只需要一句话就好
I just need your permission
我只需要你的一句允许
Why is he so serious?
他为什么要这么认真
I'm different from my dad
我跟我爹不一样
if it were me
如果是我的话
As early as the day when the disaster occurred in the Gengwu year
早在庚午年发生士祸的那天
I'll kill all the rats in your house.
就会连你家的鼠辈都杀个精光
Although I don't want to hurt him
虽然我不想伤害他
But I have to be cruel
但我要狠心一点
I have already answered you
我已经回答你了
Because of my low status
因为我的身份低微
So even rejection is insignificant?
所以就连拒绝也微不足道吗
That's not what I meant
我不是那个意思啊
Did you misinterpret it or did it on purpose?
你是曲解了  还是故意的？
What about me?
我呢
Not the kind of person who can freely say whatever he thinks
不是那种可以随意说出任何想法
Unilateral display of any emotional identity
单方面展现任何感情的身份
I must endure, hold on, hide
我必须忍着  撑着  藏着
Nothing can be shown
什么都不能表现出来
Therefore
因此
I won't be swayed by a moment of childishness
我不会因为一时的孩子气而动摇
This…
这…
it's me
就是我
the gap between you
与你之间的差距
Childish?
孩子气？
That's right
没错
Just like you said, I don't need to look at people's faces
就像你说的  我是在不用看人脸色
Growing up in an environment without any scruples
毫无顾忌的环境下长大的
I admit what I said casually
我承认我随口说出的话
It’s because you didn’t consider the other party’s confession
是没有顾虑到对方的表白
It is also a kind of love that is not respectful enough.
也是一种不够尊重的爱慕之情
I'm not curious at all about the gap you mentioned.
你所说的差距  我一点也不好奇
Because I don't need to understand
因为我不需要了解
I don’t want to pretend to understand just now
我也不想如今才来假装理解
But
但是
Even with this status
即使拥有这样的身分
Before appearing in front of the woman you like
在出现在心仪的女人面前之前
I will also practice it dozens or hundreds of times in my mind
我也会在心里反复练习数十、数百次
My steps are always heavy and hesitant
我的步伐始终沉重  犹豫不决
Usually this kind of thing
通常这种东西
everyone calls it courage
大家都称之为勇气
But you are so heartless
但你真无情
(You're my everything to me)
(You're my everything to me)
I'm leaving
我走了
(The one that attracted me)
(那股曾吸引着我的)
(named your dazzling sunshine to me)
(名为你的耀眼阳光  对我而言)
(The moment I see you again)
(再次见到你的那瞬间)
(My heart is calling you)
(我的心呼唤着你)
(We Again Again)
(我们再次    Again)
(You're my everything to me)
(You're my everything to me)
(The one that attracted me)
(那股曾吸引着我的)
(named your dazzling sunshine to me)
(名为你的耀眼阳光   对我而言)
(You're my everything to me)
(You're my everything to me)
(The moment I see you again)
(再次见到你的那瞬间)
(Being with you like a dream again)
(就像发梦般与你在一起  Again)
Mother
娘
I'm so hungry
我好饿
You stay
你待着
I'm going to get snacks
我去拿零食过来
Smelly girl, leave this house quickly.
臭丫头  快点离开这个家吧
Do that to me...
那样对我…
Are you saying that our Eunjo is going to marry your grandfather?
你说我们恩祖要嫁给你的祖父吗
What are you talking about?
你在胡说八道什么
what memory is this
这是什么记忆
The guy who sold his evil daughter to make ends meet
卖掉孽女  才勉强糊口的家伙
The wine went smoothly.
酒还喝得很顺啊
Damn...
可恶…
Mother
娘
When is Eunjo's marriage scheduled?
恩祖的婚事订在何时
There are only ten days left now
现在就剩十日了
When did father say he was going there?
父亲说什么时候要过去？
five days later
五日后
Damn it, don't care
可恶  不管了
No matter what she wants
不管她要怎样
None of my business
都不关我的事
none of my business
不关我的事
I heard you were looking for me
听说你找我
The marriage to the Middle Temple family will not be withdrawn.
与中殿家族的婚事不会撤回
Husband and wife should be of one mind
夫妻本该一心同体
I should also let my wife know that I exist
也该让我的夫人知道我的存在
If she knew I was a beast
若她知道我是个禽兽
That lady from a highly respected scholar-bureaucrat's family
那位德高望重士大夫家的小姐
How many tears will you shed?
会流多少泪呢
That despicable evil girl is willing to do it for her father
那个卑贱的孽女都愿意为了自己的父亲
Became the old man's concubine
成为老人的小妾了
Why are you mentioning that girl's name now?
现在为何会提到那丫头的名字呢
You should follow that boy Eunjo's example
你该以恩祖那孩子为榜样
You want me to shut up and be sold
你要我闭上嘴巴被卖掉
Just like that girl?
就像那个丫头一样吗
You thought that as long as it was as you said
你以为只要如你所说
Refuse to be a sowing stallion
拒绝当播种的种马
Can you keep your self-esteem?
就能守住你的自尊心吗
Enzu, that kid knows it very well
恩祖那孩子很清楚
Lowly people don't deserve that kind of thing in the first place
低贱的人从一开始就不配拥有那种东西
You cannot ask the daughter of the Middle Temple family
你不能向中殿家族的女儿
No
不
You can't identify yourself to anyone
你不能向任何人表明自己的身分
I give you name, wealth and fame
我给你的名字、财富与名誉
None of you...
你一个都…
Can't give up
舍弃不了
That's the real you
那才是真正的你
Be careful on the road
路上小心
I heard that the environment there is good and the scenery is beautiful
听说那里环境好  风景也漂亮
enjoy it
尽情享受吧
But that…
但是那个…
At least watch Eun Jo's marriage before leaving.
至少看完恩祖的婚事再离开吧
now
如今
You are the head of this family
你就是这个家的家长了
Take good care of them for me
替我好好照顾她们
Why do you put the responsibility on me?
为什么把责任推给我啊
You guy, now you also...
你这家伙  现在你也…
Really
真是的
Hello
喂
Don't you have anything to say?
你没话要说吗
It's up to you to decide your fate.
你的命运你自己看着办吧
Abominable
可恶
That guy looked like this even on the day I left.
那家伙连在我离开的日子也这副模样
I'm so sorry
真是抱歉
No
不会
Medicinal materials prepared for you
帮你准备的药材
Please ask the wine lady at the inn to cook it for you and drink it.
请知会客栈的酒母帮你煎来喝
I'm sorry for leaving you alone to prepare for the wedding.
对不起  让你独自准备婚事
No need to worry
无需担心
As long as you arrive safely
只要你平安抵达就好
I heard you've been looking for me
听说你一直在找我
Has everyone else quit?
其他人都退下了吗
Can't give you much time
无法给你太多时间
Does the Lord also know?
主上也知情吗
The incense you brought into your bedroom
你带进寝殿的香
What is its origin
其来历为何
Keep smelling that fragrance
持续闻那种香
will cause confusion
将使人神智不清
Loss of ability to discern things
丧失辨别事理的能力
In the end, it will become an empty shell that is no different from the corpse.
最终将成为与尸体没有分别的空壳
Be your guy's leader
成为你这家伙的魁儡
Lord thought it was a painkiller
主上以为那是止痛药
Let me know if you have symptoms of poisoning
若出现中毒的症状就告诉我
All agree
都承旨
Is this North Korea what you got?
你得到的是这个朝鲜吗
you guy
你这家伙
Aren't you afraid of divine punishment?
都不怕天谴吗
You said he has been doing this for several days
你说他已经连续好几天
Are you all just focusing on fishing?
都只顾着钓鱼吗
Has your Majesty ever dreamed of becoming a fisherman?
大君大人曾经梦想过成为渔夫吗
If you can’t catch a woman, then catch something else.
钓不到女人  那就钓点其他东西吧
This should be the mentality
应该是这种心态吧
To gossip behind the person's back is to stir up trouble.
在当事人背后说闲话就是在搬弄是非
If you want to say something, I will not be able to see or hear you.
你们要说就要让我看不见、听不着
Don't make me upset
不让我心烦
If you want to stir up trouble, you should also show some sincerity.
想搬弄是非也拿出点诚意来吧
This is pretense of gossiping.
这是假装在搬弄是非的啰唆
How long do you plan to do this?
你到底打算这样到何时
I need to know the answer to this
这件事我必须知道答案
Tell me when you know it too
等你知道了也告诉我吧
Really
真是的
Your Majesty
大君大人
Actually, I came to you to report something.
其实我来找你是有事禀告
Rumors about a lucky boy are spreading in the market
市集正在流传吉童的传闻
What rumors
什么传闻
I heard about the person who stole the secret record of the great minister's remonstrance on corruption.
听说偷出记载大司谏贪污秘录的人
It's Ji Tong
就是吉童
That's not a rumor, it's a fact
那不是传闻  是事实啊
That's right
就是啊
I'm also confused
我也很疑惑
Didn't you say that only the three of us know?
不是说只有我们三个知道吗
There is indeed someone who knows
的确还有一个人知道
Who?
谁？
Ji Tong
吉童
Didn't he ever ask for help hiding it?
他不是曾经要求帮忙隐瞒
What is the origin of the things you stole?
自己盗取之物的来历吗
Maybe it's because the incident became too big
或许是因为事件闹大了
This also gave him the desire to strive for fame and credit.
他也因此有了争名邀功之心
Or rather
或者说
He was taking advantage of the Maharaja from the beginning
他一开始就在利用大君大人
We need to investigate in a different direction
我们要换个方向追查
Change direction?
换方向吗
Track down the secret records
追查秘录
I understand
我懂了
When looking for the owner of the secret record, you will naturally find Ji Tong
寻找秘录主人时  自然也会找到吉童
Since it records the fact that Da Si Jian was involved in corruption,
既然上面记载着大司谏贪污的事实
person who writes secret records
撰写秘录的人
It's very possible that they are people who want to seize Da Si Jian's weakness.
极有可能就是想抓住大司谏弱点的人
You go see Da Sijian and find out what he says.
你去见大司谏  探他的口风
He is too hostile to me, so he will definitely not speak.
他对我敌意太深  肯定不会开口
Today's treatment has ended
今日施疗已经结束了
Come again next time
下次再来吧
They are the children of Guangtong Bridge
是广通桥的孩子们啊
Come here
你们过来吧
Isn’t it your wedding tomorrow?
明天不是你的婚礼吗
Go and have some rest, and take a shift with someone else.
去休息吧  也跟人换个班
Why are you like this lately?
你最近为什么这样啊
I'll sort out the rest. You can go back.
剩下的我来整理吧  你回去吧
When did you have dinner?
你们什么时候吃过饭的
If you were born as a rice insect
你们若是作为米虫出生的
I'm afraid the whole year will be a drought.
恐怕一整年都是荒年了
There is nothing to give now
现在没有东西可以布施啊
Is this also possible?
这个也可以吗
Is it for me?
是要给我的吗
This gift is too good, right?
这回礼也太好了吧
So beautiful
真好看
Use this to support
以此供养
This little monk is quite smart.
这个小和尚还挺精明啊
This is enough to re-pave the floor of the Buddhist hall.
这够给佛堂重新铺设地炕了
What about me?
那我呢
This is the bracelet that authenticates me as a big benefactor.
这是认证我为大金主的手绳
Your one tael of silver is not worthy of it
你那一两银子配不上
The kids these days don’t even reply.
最近的孩子都不回话的
He is practicing silently
他是在禁语修行
It happened to rain
偏偏下雨了
Your Majesty
大君大人
You'll catch a cold like this
你这样会感冒的
It seems like the rain won't stop tomorrow, right?
这场雨明天似乎也不会停  对吧
It seems
好像是
But…
但是…
what are you looking at
你在看什么呢
muddy water
泥水
It rained even on the wedding day
连成婚这天都在下雨
Even the weather is gloomy and gloomy
连天气都阴阴沉沉的
The rain stopped in the early morning
凌晨时雨停了
Do you think it will rain again?
你觉得还会下吗
Abominable
可恶
What's wrong? What happened?
怎么了  发生什么事了吗
Why are you so beautiful?
为什么这么漂亮啊
It would be a pity even if I granted you the title of Zhongdian
就算封你为中殿都觉得可惜
What?
什么？
Damn it, hey
可恶  喂
you are so beautiful
你这么漂亮
What do you want me to do?
要我怎么办啊
Mother
娘
Come out immediately
马上出来
Don't even think about breaking off the engagement, don't even say anything.
想都别想要退婚  也别说
Let me also live a life of power
让我也过上有权有势的生活吧
As a concubine of a powerful minister's family
以权臣家小妾的身分
With a 70-year-old man who doesn’t know when he will die?
跟一个不知何时会死的七旬老翁？
My life has changed for the better
我这是命变好了
He might lie somewhere and die without saying a word.
他可能会躺在哪里  一句话也没说就离世
I don't even need to cater to him
我甚至不需要迎合他
There is no need to observe words and expressions
也不用察言观色
What happens after that?
在那之后呢？
You plan to be a widow for the rest of your life
你打算当一辈子的寡妇
Have you never experienced love even once?
连一次爱都没经历过吗
So what
那又如何
Can that be eaten?
那能当饭吃吗
Can I get a house in exchange?
能换来房子吗
It just makes people upset for no reason.
只会平白无故让人心烦意乱
My heart is churning
内心翻腾不已
Feeling depressed all day long, feeling flustered and feeling like vomiting
成日郁闷  心慌想吐
I hate that. I don't want it.
我讨厌那样  我不要
shut up
闭嘴
The Superintendent also...
大监大人也…
No, I don't agree
不  是我不同意
Call off this marriage immediately
立刻退掉这门婚事
What about after regretting the marriage?
悔婚之后呢
Want us kicked out of this room
要我们被赶出这间屋
And then sleep on the street?
然后露宿街头吗
Then who will suffer next?
那接下来是谁要受苦
Is it my sick mother?
是生病的娘亲吗
Still young master
还是少爷
You want me to struggle alone in the quagmire again
又要让我在泥潭中独自挣扎
Don't you think it's too cruel?
不觉得太残忍了吗
I will relax and leave
我会放宽心离开
it's my fault
是我的错
It's all my fault
全都要怪我
sorry
对不起
Eunjo, I'm sorry
恩祖  对不起
I'm sorry too
我也很抱歉
Enzu
恩祖
Why did you come to my house?
你怎么会来我家
Sorry, you are a lady who has not yet left the government.
抱歉  你一个未出阁的大家闺秀
I, a strange man, call you out casually
我这个陌生男子却随意叫你出来
Come first
先进来吧
Since you are my fiancé
既然你是我的未婚夫
He's not a strange man either
也不算是什么陌生男子
You will soon regard me as a strange man
你很快就要把我当成陌生男子了
Because we will break off the engagement
因为我们会解除婚约
I don't understand what you are saying
我听不懂你在说什么
Reason for breaking off the engagement...
解除婚约的原因…
Refuse to be a sowing stallion
拒绝当播种的种马
Can you keep your self-esteem?
就能守住你的自尊心吗
The reason is... The name I gave you
原因是…　　我给你的名字
wealth and fame
财富与名誉
You are the same...
你一样都…
Can't give up
舍弃不了
That's the real you
那才是真正的你
Despicable bastard
卑鄙无耻的混蛋
If you can't let go of your friendship with that prostitute Lu Yi
若你是放不下与露乙那个妓生的情分
Then I don't care
那我并不在意
If you keep insisting that you don’t care
你如果不断强调自己不在意
At that time, I’m afraid it will really show its ugly face.
到时恐怕真的会露出介意的丑态吧
The bride must take the initiative to terminate the engagement
须由新娘主动解除婚约
It will not cause any trouble to you in the future
日后才不会对你造成后患
please stay
请留步
You didn't hesitate to come in the rain
你不惜冒雨而来
Are you really determined to solve it as soon as possible?
是真的决心要尽快解决吗
Just think of it as me struggling.
就当作我是在挣扎吧
It's raining harder again
雨又下得更大了
It's almost time to leave
差不多该出发了
Good
好
what is this
这是什么
Those are embroidered shoes
那是绣花鞋
I told you that it would get stained by muddy water, so I won’t wear embroidered shoes.
我都说会沾到泥水  不穿绣花鞋了
These are not my embroidered shoes
这并不是我的绣花鞋
That was what a young man put up together with the embroidered shoes just now.
那是刚才某位公子与绣花鞋一同摆上去的
It seems that I am worried that you will get married wearing wet shoes.
似乎是担心你穿着湿掉的鞋出嫁吧
Could it be...
该不会…
when the raindrops fall on you
当雨滴落在身上时
The depression in my heart seems to be diluted a little.
心里的郁闷似乎也会被冲淡一些
How is it possible
怎么可能
I mean it
我是说真的
Enzu, that kid knows it very well
恩祖那孩子很清楚
Lowly people don't deserve that kind of thing in the first place
低贱的人从一开始就不配拥有那种东西
She must persist
她就一定要坚持过来
what are you doing
你在做什么
what is this doing
这是在做什么
I'm going to treat you like an animal
我是打算把你当畜牲对待
How could you be so extravagant?
就凭你  怎么能如此奢糜
Do you have to sell yourself?
你就非要卖掉自己吗？
Master
老爷
The old man passed away
大老爷去世了
I'm an officer of the Bureau of Robbery
我是捕盗厅的从事官
Take me to see the prisoner
带我去见犯人
What happened? What happened?
怎么了  发生何事
Call the other officers
把其他军官叫来
Go quickly Yes
快去　　是
Ji Tong?
吉童吗
Sir
大人
what is that
那是什么
It's liquor
是烈酒
You look needy tonight
今晚你看起来很需要
Enzu
恩祖
Uncle Shi
石三叔
You haven't eaten anything all day, right?
你一整天都没吃东西吧
This is for you
这个给你
come on
来吧
How did you get in here?
你是怎样进来这里的
How else could he get in? Of course he was sold.
还能是怎样进来的  当然是被卖来的
Aren’t we all the property of two classes of nobles?
我们不都是两班贵族的财产吗
After the owner’s house was confiscated and his family was exterminated
主人被抄家灭门后
All property confiscated
全部财产都充公
Yesterday, I was sold to this family again.
昨天又被卖到这一户人家里了
Master Da Si Jian will go to the place of exile soon, right?
大司谏老爷很快就要前往流放地了吧
He is gone now
他如今已经不在了
Did he pass away? How could it be so sudden?
他过世了吗  怎么会这么突然
I'm also surprised
我也很吃惊
But what’s even more surprising is the news coming from the market
可是更令人吃惊的是集市上传出的风声
What's the news?
传出了什么风声
It is said that my father was killed by Ji Tong
据说我家老爷是吉童所杀
What is Ji Tong?
什么  吉童吗
What do you mean Ji Tong killed someone?
什么叫吉童杀人了
What's going on?
这又是怎么回事
Anyway, no one will enter the other courtyard tonight.
反正今晚不会有人进到别院
Are you hunting for Ji Dong?
你们这是在追捕吉童吗
Already investigating
已经在调查了
What else to investigate?
还要调查什么
On my master’s blood book
我家老爷的血书上
They all wrote the name Jitong
都写了吉童这个名字
A blood letter?
血书吗
Does that mean he left a last message?
意思是他留了遗言吗
before having clear evidence
在掌握明确的证据之前
Please wait a little longer
还请你再等等
No evidence was found
没能发现任何证据
Go to the Robbery Hall
去捕盗厅吧
Let's go Yes
走吧　　是
It's Ji Tong
是吉童
Ji Tong appears
吉童出现了
Ji Tong? Did someone call Ji Tong just now?
吉童吗  刚刚有人喊吉童吗
that way
往那边
You have to get up
必须起身才行
How long have I been in coma?
我昏迷多久了
Wine table?
酒桌吗
I was clearly being chased by patrol officers and soldiers just now.
我刚刚明明还在被巡逻官兵追赶
What's going on with this satin? Wait a minute.
这身绸缎是怎么回事  等等
How did my hands become like this?
我的手怎么会变成这样
Why is my head so dizzy?
头怎么这么晕
What's going on
怎么回事
why am i on the street
我为何会在街道上
Ji Tong appears
吉童出现了
Catch Ji Tong quickly
快抓住吉童
Ji Tong?
吉童吗
What's going on
怎么回事
This face…
这张脸…
Are you an official?
是从事官吗
Is anyone here?
有人在吗
Did we really exchange souls?
我们真的交换灵魂了吗
In the palace? Is this in the palace?
宫里吗  这是在宫廷中吗
Is this a dream?
这是在发梦吧
Because this is my home from yesterday
因为从昨日起  这便是我家了
It seems that there was a dispute between the couple last night
看来昨晚夫妻间经历了一番争执
who is your husband
谁是你丈夫
what makes me angry is
让我生气的是
I'm so useless that I even gave you embroidered shoes.
自己这么没用  竟然还送绣花鞋给你
Since none of the adults got up, I came in to take a look.
因为大人都没起身  我才进来一看
But the person is no longer inside
但人已经不在里面了
What does it mean that Ji Tong was arrested?
吉童被拘捕是什么意思
Go find an adult immediately
立刻去找大人